Preliminary Guide to The Thomas Hahn Chesapeake and Ohio Canal collection, 1939-1993 MS2020
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Boiler Room from reports of S. Welch: At Plane #8 3,116 ft. long (plane operation 352 ft./min.) takes 9 min. to move cars bottom to top requires 60 gals. of water as steam burns about 6# coal per min. Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 239)
- Building based on several of paintings at Head Houses. Machinery on Mr. Welch's reports: 2 engines but only one used, other is a spare. Same arrangement for boilers but had probably a connection to permit any boiler with either engine. Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 240)
- Big Wheels at head of planes each 8 ft. diameter. Horizontal sheave 9'7" diameter. 22 "- 3" diameter ropes. As conceived from original description. 30 H.P. at planes 2-5-9-10. 35 H.P. at planes 1-3-4-6-7 & 8. 2 cylinder stream engine 14" or 15" x 60" stroke 14 RPM. One engine on each side but only one engine operates, other is a spare Clutch couplings connect either. Horizontal sheave can drift 15ft. to take up slack and keep rope taut moved by weight hanging in pit. Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 241)
- Big Wheels at head of planes each 8 ft. diameter. Horizontal sheave 9'7" diameter. 22 "- 3" diameter ropes. As conceived from original description. 30 H.P. at planes 2-5-9-10. 35 H.P. at planes 1-3-4-6-7 & 8. 2 cylinder stream engine 14" or 15" x 60" stroke 14 RPM. One engine on each side but only one engine operates, other is a spare Clutch couplings connect either. Horizontal sheave can drift 15ft. to take up slack and keep rope taut moved by weight hanging in pit. Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 242)
- Passenger and freight transportation company had relay stations where horses were changed. Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 243)
- Section Boats loaded and unloaded local shipments only. The advantage the section boats had in transporting cargoes that were carried over mountains without being broken open. Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 244)
- Passenger and Burden Car used on the Allegheny Portage Railroad 1834-35. 4 wheels. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 245)
- Using a chain stop to fasten car to wire rope for hauling on the various planes. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 246)
- State owned cars 1843. 8 wheels. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 247)
- Packet Boats operated day and night. Rules required 2 lights fore and aft. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 248)
- Incline Plane No. 1 East of Johnstown. Hoist House in front of the Staple Bend Tunnel. Tunnel still standing (1972.) Bethlehem Steel now has a 48" waterline running through tunnel. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E., undated (Box 25, Folder 249)
- Staple Bend Tunnel and Hoist House. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 250)
- State owned tracks, rolling stock was privately owned, Philadelphia to Belmont Incline. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 251)
- Crew laying track for the Allegheny Portage Railroad, Hollidaysburg to Johnstown, along the various levels. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 252)
- Norris Locomotive The Geo. Washington 1836 The Bush Hill 1837. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 253)
- Hitching at the 'Foot of the Plane' using a braided hemp rope called a 'Stop', made from an old sketch and shows Iron Rails on the plane instead of wood timber with iron strap. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 254)
- Water for drinking was usually provided in a barrel, a dipper or spigot was provided. Many boats had a small bar near the kitchen, served by the cook, where drinks stronger than water could be had. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 255)
- Packet on the Penna. Canal passing Rockville Bridge crossing of Penna. Railroad over the Susquehanna River 1857-59. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 256)
- Looking for a seat in a car for travel over the Allegheny Portage Railroad. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 257)
- A 3 hammer forge along the canal. Many forges used Juniata iron, were steam driven when water was not available. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 258)
- Drawing lots for a berth. (Dickens American notes.) Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 259)
- Drawing of Early Coach (Railway) 1832 Philadelphia 1832. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 260)
- Barrels were much in use, many commodities were most easily shipped in barrels which were made in large quantities. Every village was likely to have a cooper. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 261)
- The Chimneys of the Steam Tags are jointed and in passing a viaduct the upper part is turned down, which allows the smoke to rush out at so small a height as to envelope the whole train in a dense and noisy cloud "Prolix". Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 262)
- Probable method of signaling to top of plane when cars were ready to be hauled. William Strickland saw this in England when visiting to see improvements for Penna. 1836. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 263)
- Viaduct crossing the Schuylkill 984 ft. long from an old sketch. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 264)
- The Jigger man important job, se "Canal Currents," 'Whiskey on the Canal.' Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 265)
- Rainy Day diversion, sometimes unharmonious. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 266)
- Using horses to haul passenger cars on a level before 1836. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 267)
- Cars descending Plane 6, Skew Arch. Conestoga Wagon traveling Huntingdon Indiana Turnpike. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 268)
- A family boat, usually a freighter, stables on boat runs during daylight only, wife cooks, keeps house, husband steers heavy work, boy drives and steers. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 269)
- Method of replacing tow cables on Rope Ferry. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 270)
- Activity in Johnstown Basin. Two men could pole boats, sometimes as many as 30 boats in basin at one time. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 271)
- Passing an iron works, slack water Western Division. This type of furnace went out with passing of the canal. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 272)
- Part of the Salt Works along the Western Division. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 273)
- Many coal drifts in the hillsides, not mined commercially until after 1830. Later one of the important items transported by canal. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 274)
- Salt refineries along the Western Division of the Canal. The well, pump and boiling pans. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 275)
- Some mines along the Western Division delivered coal by chutes directly into boats, undated (Box 25, Folder 276)
- On a cold rainy day passengers pass time of day inside the cabin. Politics usually debated among male passengers. Here the politician holds forth. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 277)
- Stone splitting quarries were near where the work was being done. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 278)
- On both sides of the Kiskiminitis River from Blairsville west many salt wells and refineries, visible to canal travelers. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 279)
- The aqueduct at Tunnelton from an old photo. Penna. Canal aqueduct across Conemaugh River between Livermore and Tunnelton. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 280)
- "Ladies, ladies Please! "Harriet Beecher Stowe." Excitement and chaos in the Ladies Section: Getting ready for bed. Me sleep up there! Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 281)
- The aqueduct of Freeport, across the Allegheny River. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 282)
- The Baldwin Locomotive "The Lancaster" used on the Columbia Railroad. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 283)
- Typical construction of Lock gate. The paddle is usually below the water level when it is opened. Pennsylvania Canal drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E, undated (Box 25, Folder 284)
- Passengers leaving building to board train, Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E (Box 25, Folder 312)
- 2 men running to board canal boat being towed by mules, Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E (Box 25, Folder 313)
- People in foreground facing city with train on the right, Allegheny Portage Railroad slides drawing by P.J. Hoffman P.E (Box 25, Folder 314)
- Aqueduct and Catholic College, Georgetown. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 285)
- Aqueduct Bridge and Georgetown from the Virginia bank, ca. 1860-1865 (Box 25, Folder 286)
- C&O Canal above Georgetown. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 287)
- C&O Canal above Georgetown. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 288)
- Aqueduct. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 289)
- Alexandria Canal Aqueduct, Georgetown. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 290)
- Aqueduct. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 291)
- Historical Canal. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 292)
- Canal site aerial shot. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 293)
- Tidelock Northwell. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 294)
- Potomac Aqueduct owned by the Alexandria Canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 295)
- Canal lock. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 296)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 297)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 298)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 299)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 300)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 301)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 302)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 303)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 304)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 305)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 306)
- Canal site. Excavation of the Tidelock Alexandria Canal in, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 307)
- Traing on bridge over overgrown canal with stone building on the left, undated (Box 25, Folder 308)
- Field with waterway in the back, undated (Box 25, Folder 309)
- 5 (up) lock above Harper's Ferry on the Shenandoah with sill in right backside, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 310)
- East sill 7 Lock above Harper's Ferry on the Shenandoah, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 311)
- Below Lock 38, Shepherdstown (Box 25, Folder 315)
- The Story of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 316)
- Mule carrying bundles, undated (Box 25, Folder 317)
- People walking in the forest, undated (Box 25, Folder 318)
- Wagon train in mountains, undated (Box 25, Folder 319)
- Map of old roads in Early America, undated (Box 25, Folder 320)
- Field and waterway in the distance, undated (Box 25, Folder 321)
- Boating the James, undated (Box 25, Folder 322)
- Boats meet wagon train, undated (Box 25, Folder 323)
- Person in woods with horse, undated (Box 25, Folder 324)
- People in colonial garb next to cannons, undated (Box 25, Folder 325)
- George Washington's Potowmack Canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 326)
- Great Falls, undated (Box 25, Folder 327)
- People in colonial attire, undated (Box 25, Folder 328)
- Route of the Potowmack Canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 329)
- Waterway, undated (Box 25, Folder 330)
- Canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 331)
- Bridge over waterway, undated (Box 25, Folder 332)
- People in colonial attire, undated (Box 25, Folder 333)
- People at falls, undated (Box 25, Folder 334)
- Rocks and water, undated (Box 25, Folder 335)
- Waterway, undated (Box 25, Folder 336)
- Stonework, undated (Box 25, Folder 337)
- Building a lock, undated (Box 25, Folder 338)
- Chiseled markings on a rock, undated (Box 25, Folder 339)
- People on water, undated (Box 25, Folder 340)
- Modes of transportation, undated (Box 25, Folder 341)
- Barge pulled on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 342)
- Barge and other boat on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 343)
- Map of canals, undated (Box 25, Folder 344)
- Barge being transported, undated (Box 25, Folder 345)
- Barged being placed on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 346)
- Barge being transported by rail (Box 25, Folder 347)
- Barge being transported through tunnel, undated (Box 25, Folder 348)
- Waterway, undated (Box 25, Folder 349)
- Barges on canal near buildings, undated (Box 25, Folder 350)
- Barge on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 351)
- The Old Ditch, 1828-1924, undated (Box 25, Folder 352)
- Seal of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Company, undated (Box 25, Folder 353)
- Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historic park 184.5 miles, undated (Box 25, Folder 354)
- John Quincy Adams, undated (Box 25, Folder 355)
- Canal Groundbreaking ceremony, undated (Box 25, Folder 356)
- Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, undated (Box 25, Folder 357)
- Constructing canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 358)
- Early Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, undated (Box 25, Folder 359)
- Railroad and canal barge, undated (Box 25, Folder 360)
- Railroad trestle and canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 361)
- Constructing canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 362)
- Barges on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 363)
- People fighting, undated (Box 25, Folder 364)
- Dam, undated (Box 25, Folder 365)
- Road cut, undated (Box 25, Folder 366)
- Paw Paw Tunnel, undated (Box 25, Folder 367)
- Paw Paw Tunnel, undated (Box 25, Folder 368)
- Waterway near buildings, undated (Box 25, Folder 369)
- Bridge or aqueduct, undated (Box 25, Folder 370)
- Bridge or aqueduct, undated (Box 25, Folder 371)
- Stonework tunnel, undated (Box 25, Folder 372)
- Stonework tunnel, undated (Box 25, Folder 373)
- Stonework and waterway, undated (Box 25, Folder 374)
- Dam, undated (Box 25, Folder 375)
- Stonework and waterway, undated (Box 25, Folder 376)
- Stonework waterway and bridge (Box 25, Folder 377)
- Stonework and building, undated (Box 25, Folder 378)
- Bridge and stonework in winter, undated (Box 25, Folder 379)
- Wooden building, undated (Box 25, Folder 380)
- Great Falls Tavern and Lock, undated (Box 25, Folder 381)
- Canal barge and railcar working, undated (Box 25, Folder 382)
- Canal barges on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 383)
- Barge on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 384)
- Building on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 385)
- Building on canal, undated (Box 25, Floppy disk 386)
- Building on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 387)
- Barge on canal with stonework and buildings, undated (Box 25, Folder 388)
- Great Falls Tavern and Lock, undated (Box 25, Folder 389)
- People firing cannons, undated (Box 25, Folder 390)
- Side of canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 391)
- Barges, undated (Box 25, Folder 392)
- People working, undated (Box 25, Folder 393)
- People inside house, undated (Box 25, Folder 394)
- Barge at Lock, undated (Box 25, Folder 395)
- Mule pulling barge, undated (Box 25, Folder 396)
- Barges on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 397)
- Mules, undated (Box 25, Folder 398)
- Barge and mule, undated (Box 25, Folder 399)
- Barge on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 400)
- Barge on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 401)
- Man blowing horn, undated (Box 25, Folder 402)
- Barge on canal, undated (Box 25, Folder 403)
- House at Lock, undated (Box 25, Folder 404)
- House at Lock, undated (Box 25, Folder 405)
- Barge on canal aqueduct, undated (Box 25, Folder 406)
- Dam, undated (Box 25, Folder 407)
- The End, undated (Box 25, Folder 408)
- Notecards by mile file, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Notecareds by subject file, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Miss, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Notecards of Boatmen A-Z, undated (Box SHARED Box 18, Box 27, Folder 1)
- Notecards of Locktenders, undated (Box SHARED Box 18, Box 27, Folder 2)
- Notecards ofPersonalities, undated (Box SHARED Box 18, Box 27, Folder 3)
- Notecards of other then boatmen/locktenders A-Z, undated (Box SHARED Box 18, Box 27, Folder 4)
- Notecards of Personalities other than boatmen/locktenders A-Z, undated (Box SHARED Box 18, Box 27, Folder 5)
- Notecards by Canal boats A-Z, undated (Box SHARED Box 19, Box 28, Folder 1)
- Notecards by Mile & Subject, undated (Box SHARED Box 19, Box 28, Folder 2)
- Two illustrations: The rebels retreating with their plunder across the Potomac River and The rebels destroying the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal. Harper's Weekly, 1864 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Antietam Aqueduct. n.d, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Lock tender and his family in front of his house. n.d, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Lock tenders house. n.d, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Great Falls Tavern. n.d, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Hikers on the C&O Canal. n.d, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Photoplate book of Erie Canal. n.d., undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
- When the Past Dries Up: The Story of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
- General Highway Map, Allegany County Maryland, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- General Highway Map, Fredrick County Maryland, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- General Highway Map, Fredrick County Maryland, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- General Highway Map, Montgomery County Maryland, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- General Highway Map, Washington County Maryland, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Cumberland, MD-PA-VA-WV, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Maryland and Delaware, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Washington, DC-MD-VA, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Maryland: Artemas, MD-PA-WV, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Maryland: Buckeystown, MD-VA, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Maryland: Catoctin Furnace, MD (photorevised in 1979), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Maryland: Cherry Run, MD-WV-PA, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Maryland: Cherry Run, MD-WV-PA (photorevised in 1971), 1951 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Maryland: Clear Spring, MD-PA (photorevised in 1971), 1955 (Box 30, Folder 15)
- Maryland: Cumberland, MD-PA-WV, 2 maps, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 16)
- Maryland: Evitts Creek, MD-PA-WV, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 17)
- Maryland: Funkstown, MD (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 18)
- Maryland: Hagerstown, MD-PA (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 19)
- Maryland: Hancock, WV-MD-PA (photorevised 1971), 1951 (Box 30, Folder 20)
- Maryland: Hughesville, MD (photorevised 1974), 1956 (Box 30, Folder 21)
- Maryland: La Plata, MD (photorevised 1985), 1956 (Box 30, Folder 22)
- Maryland: Mason-Dixon, MD-PA copy 1 (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 23)
- Maryland: Mason-Dixon, MD-PA copy 2 (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 24)
- Maryland: Middletown, MD (photorevised 1979), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 25)
- Maryland: Myersville, MD (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 26)
- Maryland: Oldtown, MD-WV, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 27)
- Maryland: Patterson Creek, MD-WV, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 28)
- Maryland: Point of Rocks, MD-VA, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 29)
- Maryland: Poolesville, MD-VA, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 30)
- Maryland: Popes Creek, MD (photorevised 1974), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 31)
- Maryland: Seneca, MD-VA, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 32)
- Maryland: Smithburg, MD-PA (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 33)
- Maryland: Washington, DC-MD-VA, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 34)
- Maryland: Williamsport, MD-WV, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 35)
- Maryland: Williamsport, MD-WV (photorevised 1971), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 36)
- Pennsylvania: Big Cove Tannery, PA (photorevised 1973), 1967 (Box 30, Folder 37)
- Pennsylvania: Greencastle, PA (photorevised 1973), 1944 (Box 30, Folder 38)
- Pennsylvania: Masontown, PA (photorevised 1979), 1964 (Box 30, Folder 39)
- Pennsylvania: Williamson, PA (photorevised 1973), 1944 (Box 30, Folder 40)
- Virginia Falls Church, VA-MD, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 41)
- Virginia Hayfield, VA (photorevised 1972), 1965 (Box 30, Folder 42)
- Virginia Leesburg, VA-MD, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 43)
- Virginia Middletown, VA (photorevised 1972), 1966 (Box 30, Folder 44)
- Virginia Mount Vernon, VA-MD (photorevised 1983), 1966 (Box 30, Folder 45)
- Virginia Sterling, VA-MD, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 46)
- Virginia Waterford, VA-MD, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 47)
- Virginia White Hall, VA-WV, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 48)
- West Virginia: Big Pool, WV-MD copy 1, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 49)
- West Virginia: Big Pool, WV-MD copy 2, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 50)
- West Virginia: Capon Bridge, WV-VA, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 51)
- West Virginia: Cresaptown, WV-MD, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 52)
- West Virginia: Glengary, WV-VA, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 53)
- West Virginia: Great Cacapon, WV-MD, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 54)
- West Virginia: Hedgesville, WV-MD, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 55)
- West Virginia: Inwood, WV-VA (photorevised 1979), 1966 (Box 30, Folder 56)
- West Virginia: Lake Lynn, PA-WV (photorevised 1976), 1960 (Box 30, Folder 57)
- West Virginia: Levels, WV, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 58)
- West Virginia: Masontown, WV (photorevised 1976), 1960 (Box 30, Folder 59)
- West Virginia: Middleway, WV, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 60)
- West Virginia: Morgantown, WV-PA (photorevised 1976), 1957 (Box 30, Folder 61)
- West Virginia: Morgantown, WV (photorevised 1976), 1957 (Box 30, Folder 62)
- West Virginia: Osage, WV-PA (photorevised 1976), 1958 (Box 30, Folder 63)
- West Virginia: Paw Paw, WV-MD, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 64)
- West Virginia: Petersburg, WV, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 65)
- West Virginia: Ridge Quadrangle, WV-VA, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 66)
- West Virginia: Rivesville, WV (photorevised 1976), 1960 (Box 30, Folder 67)
- West Virginia: Romney Quadrangle, WV, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 68)
- West Virginia: Round Hill, WV-VA, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 69)
- West Virginia: Smithburg, WV (photorevised 1976), 1961 (Box 30, Folder 70)
- West Virginia: Springfield, WV copy 1, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 71)
- West Virginia: Springfield, WV copy 2, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 72)
- West Virginia: Stotlers, WV, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 73)
- West Virginia: Tablers, WV, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 74)
- West Virginia: Upper Tract, WV (photorevised 1981), 1969 (Box 30, Folder 75)
- West Virginia: Wardensville, WV-VA, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 76)
- Mules along towpath at Riley's Lock, No. 24, at Seneca, Md., undated (Box SHARED Box 19, Box 31, Folder 1)